Ruby lover, Polyglot developer, eager to learn new tech, set out to make machines do heavy-liftings for humanity

Summary

"Solves our issues" As an engineer, I solve problems after helping to define them.

"Competent communicator" I am effective when working with both devs and non-devs, of any cultural

backgrounds from Europe to the Far East

"Fast learner" I explore the new hype but aim to exploit the tested tech.

"Self-driven" I strive to see the team's as well as personal achievement and growth.

Skills

Agile, Scrum

Test driven development (rspec, mocha, jasmine, ginkgo)

Ruby(Rails or not), Golang, Python, NodeJS,

• Relational databases(MySQL, SQLite, Postgresql)

NoSQL: MongoDB

• RabbitMQ, Redis, Memcache

JAVA, Android Development

AWS Services: EC2, RDS, Route53

Docker

DNS Routing, Apache Server, NginX

• Operations Research, Design Thinking, Data Analytics, Simulation

• Fluency in English (written and spoken), Khmer(written and spoken), Mandarin(spoken)

Experience

Roomorama.com: Full Stack Developer Mar 2016 - Present

- Build new integrations with supplier and distributor to share inventory using Hanami Framework (Ruby)
- Develop and maintain internal Ruby libraries and gems
- Troubleshoot bugs under time and financial pressures
- Code reviews and pair programming to improve quality of code
- Create internal tools to monitor inventory integration status
- Test and maitain legacy application (Ruby on Rails)
- Introduce React to the website frontend
- Cleanup legacy code (Backbone) and revamp frontend to backend data flow

Gimmie.io: Full Stack Developer

Nov 2013 - Mar 2016

- Manage a team of 3 developers to build an MVP, using Rails and Golang on Heroku
- Built an analytics pipeline to collect, process and store incoming click stream data
- Built a machine-learning-based article recommendation engine (python)
- Built a WYSIWYG editor for clients to edit engagement contents, such as recommendation
- Designed and built concurrent workers utilizing golang's concurrency, resulting in efficient, easily scalable architecture
- Set up and maintain Docker images which leads to faster deploy to staging and production environments
- Test-driven-development in Rails(rspec) and Golang(gomega)

- Added Shopify API integration to MVP, resulting in more beta installs from listing in Shopify App Listings
- Migrated MVP away from Heroku and added rabbitmq on top of Postgresql, MongoDB using AWS EC2 and RDS
- Built a NodeJS app that starts PhantomJS and outputs the screenshot of a url
- Maintain and support Android library on Unity 3 and 4, powering the gamification of client apps
- Built a Magento plugin for easier integration, and wider exposure of Gimmie Loyalty

St'aime: Founder and Android Develor

May 2013 - Nov 2013

- Developed a rewards system with integrated social media marketing for retail shops in Cambodia
- Attracted 3 businesses in Phnom Penh with a combined revenue of US\$30k for collaboration

NUS: Teaching Assistant

Aug 2011 - Nov 2013

- Taught programming methodology to 150 students in 6 classes
- Volunteered time for small group consultation sessions to help weaker students catch up

Selected Projects

- Foosorama An angular/rails app to keep track of office foosball scores
- GrabABouquet A rails Spreecommerce app that sold flowers during Valentine's Day.
- <u>Flappy-bird mod</u> A hack of a popular game, modifying it for use as a quiz in classrooms. Entertained some sec2 kids.
- <u>Follodota</u>: An android app to aggregate professional DotA matches replays.
- Bounce Ball casual game: a cross-platform game that generate an average of 30 replays each session
- <u>English Repeat</u>: an English learning application which achieved high engagement and ratings from the target audience: my parents.
- <u>Give and Take (NUS Freecycling project)</u> Proposed and executed collections of recycled items, and the
 giveaway sessions at the start of the new semester; Donated more than 100kg of non-reusable materials;
 gave away many more items for reuse

Education

National University of Singapore

BEng (Industrial and System Engineering) with Design Centric Program

Aug 2010 - May 2014

- Holder of NUS ASEAN Undergraduate Scholarship
- NUS Dean's List Certificate (top 5% of the cohort) 2010/2011 SemI&II

Loves

Ruby(see here), Top-rope climbing, TED Talks, CS Lewis, Badminton, Soccer, Dota2, Bass guitar